Guide to the Nancy Booker Morey papers,1933-1944.
Morey, Nancy Booker papers,1933-1944.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nancy Booker Morey papers, 1933-1944.
23-14-1465
Nancy Booker, Morey 1903-
.1 cubic ft.
Pamphlets, articles, and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes pamphlets concerning economics; articles by Morey concerning nutrition and the energy value of diets; and correspondence with J. Lossing Buck, L. A. Maynard, Lydia J. Roberts, Sybil L. Smith, Henry C. Sherman, Hildegard Kneeland, Mary S. Rose, Francis G. Benedict, Helen W. Atwater, Ruth Moore, Thorne M. Carpenter, E. P. Cathcart, F. C. Kelly, Faith M. Williams, Jonnie McCrery, John Leont'Ev, Milicent L. Hathaway, and Helen Canon.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes pamphlets concerning economics; articles by Morey concerning nutrition and the energy value of diets; and correspondence with J. Lossing Buck, L. A. Maynard, Lydia J. Roberts, Sybil L. Smith, Henry C. Sherman, Hildegard Kneeland, Mary S. Rose, Francis G. Benedict, Helen W. Atwater, Ruth Moore, Thorne M. Carpenter, E. P. Cathcart, F. C. Kelly, Faith M. Williams, Jonnie McCrery, John Leont'Ev, Milicent L. Hathaway, and Helen Canon.
Cornell University M.S. 1926, Ph.D. 1931.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Morey, Nancy Booker, 1903-; Atwater, Helen W.; Benedict, Francis Gano, 1870-1957.; Buck, John Lossing, 1890-; Canon, Helen, b. 1888.; Carpenter, Thorne Martin, 1878-; Cathcart, E. P.; Hathaway, Milicent L.; Kelly, F. C.; Kneeland, Hildegard.; Leont'Ev, John.; Maynard, L. A.; McCrery, Jonnie.; Moore, Ruth.; Roberts, Lydia J.; Rose, Mary S.; Sherman, Henry C.(Henry Clapp), b. 1875.; Smith, Sybil L.; Williams, Faith M.
Subjects:
Economics.; Nutrition.; Nutritionists.; Women college teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- J. Lossing Buck to Nancy Booker Morey with enclosure - May 11, 1933 (carbon copy) L.A. Maynard to J. L. Buck, 3pp., June 21, 1933 (Box 1)
- NBM to Lydia J. Roberts (carbon copy), 2pp., June 5, 1934 (Box 1)
- LJR to NBM, July 9, 1934 (Box 1)
- NBM to Sybil L. Smith (carbon copy), 1p, July 11, 1934 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 2pp, July 21, 1934 (Box 1)
- NBM to Henry C. Sherman (typescript draft), 1p, Nov. 26, 1934 (Box 1)
- NBM to LJR (carbon copy), 1p, Nov. 27, 1934 (Box 1)
- NBM to LJR, 1p, Dec. 7, 1934 (Box 1)
- NBM to Hildegarede Kneeland (carbon copy), 1p, Jan. 22, 1935 (Box 1)
- Mary S. Rose to NBM, 1p, Mar. 11, 1935 (Box 1)
- incomplete NBM to Francis G. Benedict (typescript draft), 1p, Apr. 16, 1935 (Box 1)
- FGB to NBM, 1p, Apr. 27, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to Helen W. Atwater (carbon copy), 1p, May 7, 1935 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, May 10, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to SLS, 1p, May 13, 1935 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, May 15, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to SLS (carbon copy),1p, May 17, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to Ruth Moore (carbon copy), 1p, May 22, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to Ruth M (carbon copy), 1p, n.d (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, June 4, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to Thorne M. Carpenter (carbon copy), 1p, June 7, 1935 (Box 1)
- HWA to NBM, 1p, June 10, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to HWA (carbon copy), 1p, June 14, 1935 (Box 1)
- TMC to NBM, 1p, June 18, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to TMC (carbon copy), 1p, June 25, 1935 (Box 1)
- TMC to NBM, 2pp, June 28. 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to E. P. Cathcart (carbon copy), 1p, July 5, 1935 (Box 1)
- EPC to NBM, 2pp, July 30, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to ECP (carbon copy), 1p, Aug. 19, 1935 (Box 1)
- EPC to NBM, 1p, Aug, 29, 1935 (Box 1)
- EPC to NBM (both sides), 1p, Oct. 10, 1935 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Oct. 26, 1935 (Box 1)
- HWA to NBM, 1p, Nov. 13, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to HWA (from Rochester, resigned from C.U., typescript draft), 1p, Nov. 15, 1935 (Box 1)
- NBM to SLS (typescript draft), 1p, Jan 3, 1936 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Jan. 14, 1936 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Jan. 24, 1936 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Mar. 4, 1936 (Box 1)
- MSR to NBM, 1p, Apr. 6, 1936 (Box 1)
- MSR to NBM, 1p, Apr. 25, 1936 (Box 1)
- F.C. Kelly (Scotland) to NBM, 1p, May 25, 1936 (Box 1)
- FCK to NBM, 1p, June 15, 1936 (Box 1)
- FCK to NBM, 1p, July 22, 1936 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Aug. 12, 1936 (Box 1)
- Faith M. Williams to NBM, 1p, Aug. 28, 1936 (Box 1)
- HWA to NBM, 1p, Sept. 3, 1936 (Box 1)
- FGB to NBM, 1p, Oct. 15, 1936 (Box 1)
- Jonnie McCrery to NBM, 1p, Oct. 26, 1936 (Box 1)
- John Leont'Ev (Moscow), 1p, Apr. 7, 1937 (Box 1)
- TMC, 1p, Nov. 11, 1937 (Box 1)
- Milicent L. Hathaway, 1p, Feb. 12, 1938 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, June 13, 1940 (Box 1)
- SLS to NBM, 1p, Jan. 16, 1941 (Box 1)
- SLS to Helen Canon (with Dr. L.A. Maynard's report, Mar. 11, 1944 ), 5pp, May 3, 1944 (Box 1)
- HC to NBM (postcard), May 6, 1944 (Box 1)
- 13 postcards requesting reprints, also one from Shanghai, Sept. 1939, 1936-1939 (Box 1)
- F.C. Kelly, Scotland, to Sybil L. Smith (negative photostat), 1p, Feb. 11, 1936 (Box 1)
- F.C. Kelly, Scotland, to Sybil L. Smith (negative photostat), 1p, Feb. 17, 1936 (Box 1)
- Bound volume of Mimeo articles by Herbert J. Davenport, "The Economics of Fashion" 12pp (transferred to #14/10/1166), before 1913 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet - "The Post-War Outlook," by Herbert J. Davenport. Reprint from American Economic Review, Vol. XI, No. 1 (transferred to #14/10/1166), Mar. 1921 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet - "Wage Theory and Theories," by HJD. Reprint from American Economic Review, Vol. XXXIII, Feb. 1919 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet - "Non-Competing Groups," by HJD. Reprint fro Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol. XL, Nov. 1922 (Box 1)
- "The War-Tax Paradox," by HJD. Reprint from American Economic Review, Vol. IX, No. 1, Mar. 1919 (Box 1)
- Review of Glenn R. Morrow's book, The Ethics of the Wealth of Nations, by HJD with Morrow's reply. Reprint from Philosophical Review, Vol. XXXIV, No. 6, Nov. 1925 (Box 1)
- Mimeo stencil by NBM - "The Energy Requirements of Farm Women" (2 copies), 17pp, Apr. 1935 (Box 1)
- Mimeo stencil by NBM - "The Differences between Rubner's Factors and Atwater's Factors for Calculating the Physiological Fuel Value of a Mixed Diet", 17pp, Apr. 1935 (Box 1)
- Mimeo stencil by NBM - "Different Interpretations of Energy Value of Diets and of Energy Standards," 11pp (Box 1)
- Mimeo stencil by NBM - "Dietary Scales in Relation to the Food Consumption of New York Farm Families," 19pp, Aug. 1935 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet - "An Analysis and Comparison of Different Methods of Calculating the Energy Value of Diets," Reprinted from Nutrition Abstracts and Reviews, Vol. 6 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet - "Fat Digestion, Absorption, and Assimilation in Man and Animals as Determined by the Dark-Field Microscope and a Fat-Soluable Dye," by Simon Henry Gage and Pierre Augustine Fish. Reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy, Vol. 34, No. 1, 1936-1937 (Box 1)